### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/lokanath-panda-0a0292117 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Domo

Alteryx BI + Visualization Solutions
Microsoft Office

### Languages

English

### Certifications

Domo Technical Certification
SQL Training
PowerBi Certified
DATA SCIENCE WITH PYTHON
FREE AWS Beginners Course

### **Publications**

makebelieve

# Lokanath panda

Senior Consultant/Data Research Associate/Sr Data Analyst/Data Analyst/IT Executive skills covered: Tableau|PowerBi|Excel Vba|Sql| snowflake|Machine Learning|Python| R programing| SAS | Alteryx Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

# Summary

IT professional with 5+ yrs. Experienced as a Data Analyst with a demon-strated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in SQL, PowerBI, Microsoft Excel, Data Visualisation (Tableau), Data Mining Techniques, Data Cleaning Techniques

By Profession - Data Analyst

I always loved creating things, right from school. When computers and internet became common place, I realized I loved browsing, researching, and playing with Data. My interests took me from being a engineer to a Data Analyst/BI Developer/Data Scientist/Machine Learning Engineer

Everything I've learned along the way is helping me in adding greater values on my work or you can say Love for Analysis.

#Tableau # Powerbi #SQL#Advanced Excel #Python Programming, #AWS, #, SAS, #Alteryx, #R

# Experience

HCL Technologies Senior Consultant July 2022 - Present (1 year) Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Mitchell Martin Inc.

Data Reserch Associate

May 2021 - June 2022 (1 year 2 months)

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Mitchell Martin:

Mitchell Martin, Inc. (MMI) head quartered in New York, USA is a Talent Acquisition Solutions leader that is powered by innovation and driven by integrity. Mitchell Martin (India) Pvt. Ltd is a 100% subsidiary to Mitchell Martin Inc, located in Hyderabad, India.

#### Roles \$ Responsibility:

Wrote the code for a scalable ETL pipeline built upon the Snowflake API using SQL

Having Experience in Sql, Snowflake, Power Bi, Tableau, Advanced Excel Summarize & analyze – provide summaries of data in Excel through summary & pivot tables

Transform – manually convert data into formats required for loading into data warehouse and destination systems. Continue advance automation and programmatic transformation routines into this process.

Produced attractive visuals/dashboards to convey the story inside the data. Built dashboards using techniques for guided analytics, interactive dashboard design, and visual best practices.

Extract – public data sources where data needs to be programmatically and or manually captured.

Load – store data in the warehouse while accounting for reconciliation and scheduling

Organize – manually and programmatically organize data that is pulled from sources in the data warehouse

Communicate effectively with colleagues and business users.

Worked in all phases of BW/BI full life cycles including analysis, design, development, testing, deployment, post-production support/maintenance, documentation.

# Integrated Clean Room Technology Limietd (Hyderabad) Engineer

June 2019 - May 2021 (2 years)

Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India

Data analyst having experience in data collection, migration, filtering, cleaning, data modifying, data extraction, SQL, Excel, powerbi, Tableau Visualization Created dashboards for analyzing POS data using Tableau 8.0.

Consistently attended meetings with the client subject matter experts to acquire functional business requirements.

Developed case studies to understand new product launch, promotion effectiveness, trend detections, Seasonal forecasting.

Created Scatter Plots, Stacked Bars, Box and Whisker plots using reference, Bullet charts, Heat Maps, Filled Maps and Symbol Maps according to deliverable specifications.

Expert level capability in Tableau calculations and applying complex, compound calculations to large, complex data sets

Created custom Function's Date range, Time functions, array functions, and Conditional formatting functions in the reports.

Scheduled extract refresh for weekly and monthly reports.

Worked on workbook Permissions, Ownerships and User filters.

GreenPoint Global
Data Analyst
January 2018 - June 2019 (1 year 6 months)
Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

GreenPoint Global provides content, process and technology solutions and services to publishers, insurers, law firms, banks, schools, and educators through our subject matter experts and process specialists. Our solutions range from specialized litigation support and compliance, financial analytics, to software development. Founded in 2001 and headquartered in Rye, New York, GreenPoint has grown to over 380 employees with a global footprint. We have a stable and growing client base that ranges from small and medium-sized organizations to Fortune 1000 companies worldwide. Our production and management teams are located in the US, India, and Israel with access to deep pools of subject matter experts.

#### Roles:

Having Knowledge in Data Collection, Data Building, Data Cleaning, Gap Filling, Data Qc By using Excel advanced formula (If,sumif,h&vlookup) worked for PMS also

Reviewed data and classified the tables/measures functions by using multiple queries, views and procedures

Designed database schema contains over 30 tables such as users, groups, threads and posts

Established the connection between legacy system and Discuz forum software using MySQL and SQL Server

Migrated data from legacy system to Discuz through SQL Server and completed 99% records mapping

Resolved kinds of software or database related issues such as data loading and migration

Embee Software Pvt. Ltd.

### It Excutive

March 2017 - August 2017 (6 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Embee is a frontrunner in the technology services industry. With expertise built over decades, Embee seeks to make IT easier for organizations. From enterprises to start-ups, our customers are our partners, whom we help to achieve business outcomes by leveraging technology. Over the years, Embee has also become the leading Cloud solution provider with one of the highest Cloud mix and active Cloud usage in India. Till date, it has migrated over 500+ customers and 300,000+ users to the Cloud.

#### Roles:

handling all it equipments, having knowledge in networking system trouble shooting, cctv, biomatic, fire access, Bms, excel, asset Management

## Education

Kalam Institute of Technology (KIT), Berhampur Bachelor of Engineering - BTECH, Mechanical Engineering · (May 2013 - July 2016)